OK googlethalli.com [Music] I will compare Lombard's Elevate plan, which
is a recently launched plan,
with RISH 2.0, Niva
Bappa, SDFC R Go, Optima Secure Care,
Health's Care Supreme, Aditya Birla's
Active One plan, and Star Health's Star
Assure plan. So stay tuned
till the end of my video. If you have
visited our channel for the first time today, then subscribe to our channel
now and press the bell icon.
Also, share this video with
your friends and relatives
because this information is
very useful for everyone. If you want to purchase your insurance
through Insurance Seva, then
you can also call us on the number given on the screen.
[Music] According to
me, the first point for comparing Fox health insurance plans should be the
brand image of the insurance company and the fundamentals of the insurance company
because a
health insurance company with a good brand image and a
health insurance company with good fundamentals will
not unnecessarily reject your health insurance claim. So, first of all, I  I will
start with the fundamentals of insurance companies. Let's
first talk about
ICICI Lombard. ICICI
Lombard's claim settlement ratio is 99, which is
excellent. If we talk about its income claim ratio, it is
78, which is also fantastic. Their
solvency is 2.5, which means
they have two and a half
times more assets and money against their total liability. This is
trimendous. Talking about network hospitals,
they have 15,000 plus network
hospitals and their reimbursement
claim process is fully online. They have an
app called iCare.
Through iCare app, you can avail all the services
and also process your reimbursement claim.
Talking about ADFC
Ergo, ADFC Ergo's claim
settlement ratio is also 99, which is a very good
claim settlement ratio. Their income claim
ratio is at 79, which is up to the mark. Their
solvency is  1.68 means against total liability,
they
have assets and
money of 168 per cent. They have network hospitals of 14000 plus
and their
reimbursement claim process is online.
You can get your claim settled by sending all the claim documents to ker@hdfcergo.com. Now let's
talk about Aditya Birla's Active One
plan or Aditya Birla's
fundamentals.
With a claim settlement ratio of 96 per cent, it has an income claim ratio of
64.6. Its solvency is 1.73. It has
network hospitals of 11000
and their claim process will also be
online. The reimbursement claim process will be online.
Niva b 92 claim settlement ratio up to the
mark 54. Its income claim ratio will be 1.77.
Its solvency will be 11000 plus
network hospitals and its
reimbursement claim process will be online. A link
You can upload all your documents and
settle your claim.
Talking about Star Health, its claim
settlement ratio is 81, slightly lower at
65. Its unearned claim ratio is 1.88,
its solvency will be 14,000 plus, and it has
network hospitals. However,
its claim process and reimbursement claim
process is completely offline. No word like 'online' is
used in its claim process.
You have to submit all the documents to its head
office or branch, only
then your claim is settled.
Talking about Care Health Insurance,
its claim settlement ratio is
87, its unearned claim ratio is 53.82,
its solvency will be 1.81, and it
has network hospitals of 99.4. Its
reimbursement claim process is both online and
offline.
So now let's talk about the
special features of all these six health insurance plans.
About ICICI Lombard's Elevate plan, because this plan has been
launched recently and this plan has
captured a lot of market share in the market
and has become quite famous. This plan has
unique features because of which all the
special features are unlimited.
They have given an option of unlimited time
limit in it, that is,
apart from 10 lakh, 20 lakh, 50 lakh, they have
given an unlimited time limit option.
Unlimited time limit means that you
can use any amount of time limit.
You can use n number of claim time limit. Along with this,
you have an additional cover. If you
opt for a lower time limit, opt for a time limit of 10-20 lakh
and take an add-on cover in which you can take care of it,
then you
can take unlimited claim once in your lifetime. For example,
if you
take a time limit of ₹ 1 lakh and after 10 years or 20
years you feel that there is a big problem then  If a claim is coming in and you have a
disease that will require a
lot of claim usage, then
you can take an unlimited claim. This is also called
trimendous info cumate bonus power booster.
This is an add-on feature. If
you add this, your time should accrue up
to an number of times.
By eliminating all the x's,
they have said that if you are opting for a time shod of ₹1 lakh and
taking the power booster add-on, then there will be no accrual of ₹1 lakh every year.
This is an excellent
feature, a customer friendly feature. Next is
efficacious assurance, that is, jump start
if you have any one of the five diseases, you
can see on my screen: diabetes, hypertension,
hyperlipidemia, obesity, or
asthma. If you have any one
or more of these diseases, then by taking jump
start add-on, you
can get cover for all these diseases from 31 days. This is also a
good
efficacy. Next, they have
also covered bariatric surgery in this. It is
covered up to time.
You can claim for maternity in this, after two years
they have covered maternity, you can
reduce it to one year also,
10 per cent of the basic sum assured and ₹1 lakh
maximum, you can claim for maternity in this, so these are
the special features of
III Lord Elevate plan, let me talk about the
special features of ADAC AGO's Optima Secure,
so here are Secure Benefit,
Protect Benefit, Plus Benefit and
Optima Super Secure, first of all we will talk about
Secure Benefit, Secure Benefit
is Buy One Get One Free, if you take a policy of 10 lakhs,
you will get a cover of 20 lakhs
from the very first day, if you take a policy of 50 lakhs,
you will get a cover of 1 crore from the very first day,
Product Benefit will not be in-built consumerist in this
Optima Super Secure, if you
take Optima Super Secure, then you will have to pay the premium of 3 years
together, you will
get a discount in the premium and along with that you will get
additional 100% time, that is
If you are taking Optimus Super Secure, a policy of ₹10 lakh, then
you will get a cover of 30 lakh from day one.
₹1 lakh base term cover and ₹1 lakh
secure benefit and ₹1 lakh super secure
cover. This is also a good feature. Now let me talk about
Aditya Birla's Active One plan.
Here you are given chronic care cover.
Similarly, if you have
diabetes, hypertension,
hyperlipidemia, obesity or asthma,
then by paying additional premium you
can get cover for all these diseases from day one.
Reduction in waiting period:
You can reduce all your waiting periods by paying additional
premium.
Durable equipments are covered in this. It is an
add-on cover. There are many durable
equipments which are
prescribed by the doctor, there are crutches, there are
wheelchairs, cover of all these durable
equipments can be taken in this as a don rider.
Compassionate Travel  You will get ₹5000000
if these shorts get sick in any other city,
whatever fare is there for going there, whichever is
their close relative, can be
claimed,
its limit will be 0000 HIV AIDS
mental illness is covered in it
Treatment of obesity i.e.
cover of bariatric surgery has also been added in it
Now I will talk about
what are the special features in Niva Bupa's Re 2.0, so
here is Lock the Clock With Lock the Clock
entry, you will lock your age
and until you do not make a claim, your premium will
not increase due to age, it will
increase even if it is due to inflation Lock the Clock will
only lock your age, will
not lock inflation Booster Plus has four
variants here Bronze, Gold, Platinum and
Titanium Whatever time you have sold in Bronze will be carried
forward every year till it becomes 3x,
remaining time in Gold till it becomes 10x,
in Platinum till it becomes 5x and in Titanium
also your sum assured will be carried forward  It will accrue till 10 years, that is,
your policy of Rs 10 lakh is going to become
Rs 1 crore 10 lakh in 10 years
if you have not made any claim.
Third, there is ReAssure
Forever. ReAssure Forever means that once
your restoration is triggered,
it will remain triggered for life time.
Unlimited restoration will be for the same person, same
illness. Talking about Star Health's
StarAssure, here is
Assist Reproduction Treatment, that is,
whatever infertility treatment or
many treatments related to it,
all those treatments will be covered in it,
whose waiting period will be two years
and the sub-limit will be from Rs 1 lakh to Rs 4
lakh. The time-bound repatriation of
mortal remains has been covered by them,
its limit has been kept at Rs 000, that is,
if any insured dies during treatment somewhere far away from his city,
then his
mortal remains will be covered for bringing his dead body.  The
expenses of up to Rs. 1000 will be covered.
Uterine fetal surgery is covered in this.
Treatment in Valued Network: If
you get your treatment done in their preferred network, then
you will get
hospital cash facility of Rs. 1000 per day. Let me talk about
Care Health Insurance's Care
Supreme Plan, in which you can get instant cover.
You can reduce the
waiting period of PD by paying additional premium for hypertension, diabetes, asthma and hyperlipidemia.
And here is the
Super Cumulative Bonus add-on cover. If you take it, then
your term cover will increase up to Rs. 500
and will never be reduced in life. So these are the
special features of all
six health insurance plans. Now I will talk about the
basic features of these health insurance plans. ICICI Lombard's
Elevate Plan will have sum cover options ranging from Rs.
5 lakh to unlimited - Rs. 5 lakh,
75 lakh, 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh, 50 lakh, 1
crore, 2 crore, 3 crore and unlimited
time.  You can opt for the sum option in it.
ADFC Arg will have sum options starting from ₹5 lakh to
₹1 crore.
Aditya Birla Active One will have
sum option starting from ₹1 lakh to ₹6 crore.
Niva Bupa Rish will start from ₹2.2 lakh.
You can avail sum option of ₹75 lakh, 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh, 50 lakh and ₹1 crore here. Star
Health has sum option starting from ₹5 lakh
to ₹1 crore.
Sum option of ₹1 lakh will
also be available here. Care Health's
Care Supreme will have sum option of ₹5 lakh, 7 lakh, 10 lakh, 15
lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh, 50 lakh and ₹1 crore
available. If
we talk about entry age, here
if we talk about ICICI  Talking about Lombard's Elevate
plan, the minimum entry age will be
18 years but there will be no maximum entry age. A
person of any age
can enroll in this policy. Telemedical will be available after 55 years, that is,
if you are taking the policy before 55 years and it
is Jet Standard and there is no PD declaration, then a
State Away policy will be issued.
For those aged 55 years or above,
your policy will be issued with telemedical.
HDFC R Go Optima
Secure has a minimum entry age of 18 years. Now
they have also removed their maximum entry age and made
it unlimited, that is, a
person of any age
can take this plan, but if your age is 50, 65 or
above, then you will have to undergo a medical test
before enrolling in the policy. Aditya Birla's minimum age will be 18 years
and there will be no maximum entry
limit, but Niva Bappa Rio 2.0,
only a person between 18 years to 65 years can enroll in
this policy.  You can take Star Asher. The
minimum age will be 18 years and the maximum will
be 75 years, but after 65, the options of Rs 75 lakh, Rs 1
crore and Rs 2 crore will not be available.
In Care Health, the minimum entry age will be 18 years
and there will be no limit on maximum entries.
You can avail premium discount by paying premium for 1 year, 2 years and 3 years in six policies of policy tenure six.
Talking about variants, there are
no variants in IIC Lombard Elevate, which is a single policy.
Optima Secure has Global and
Global Plus, by taking Global Plus you
can avail treatment outside India. Aditya
Builder has Max Vital Saver VIP and
VIP Plus. Niva Bappa's Bas, as
I told you,
options of Bronze, Gold, Platinum and Titanium will be
available in Rish 2.0. There will be no variants of any kind in Star Health and Care.
Family size IIC Lombard policy can be taken for two adult three kits.
In ADAC Arg, two adult four  Policy can be taken for
two adults and four kids Aditya Build Active will be for two adults and four kids
Niva Bupa RISH 2.0 will also be
for two adults and four kids Policy can be taken for two adults and three kids in Star Health and
maximum two adults and two kids in Care Health Insurance Let's
talk about
room rent which is a very important
part for any health insurance
policy because all expenses are linked with room rent
In IACI Lord Elevate plan
you will get claim for in-build single private AC room
Apart from single private AC room, if you
want you can opt for any room category in it, there will be
add-on cover and by
reducing single private room you
can also opt for twin sharing room there
you will get discount in premium, that is all
three options are
available with them You can take benefit of single private any room
category or twin sharing room
For that
you will get additional premium or discount in premium
ADFC Ergo Aditya Billa
Niva Bupa no capping  There is no copayment in these
plans. In Star Health, the limit of 1 per cent of
the time limit will be for ₹1 lakh, which means if you
take a sum of ₹5 lakh, you will
get a maximum room rate of ₹000. There will be
no capping in policies of ₹10 lakh or more. There is no capping
on room rent in Care Health either. Let's
talk about the next feature, ICU. There is no
sub-limit or capping in the six ICCU plans.
Talking about copayment,
ICICI Lombard has
not imposed any mandatory copayment,
but it is optional. There will be no copayment of any kind
in ADFC, Aergo, Aditya Billa, Niva, Bupa or Care.
But in Star Health's Star Assure,
if your A is 61 or more, then
you will have to pay a copayment of 10 per cent on every claim.
Pre and post hospitalization
expenses before going to the hospital,
doctor's fees, expenses of your diagnostic blood
tests, expenses of your medicines, same as
your expenses after returning from the hospital.
In Lombard Elevate plan, you can claim expenses incurred 90 days in advance
and expenses incurred after 180 days.
In ADFC R Go Optima Secure, there will be 60 days pre and 180 days
post cover. In Aditya Birla also, there will be 90 days
pre and 180 days post cover.
In Niva Bapsh 2.0, you will get claim for 60 days pre
hospitalization and 180 days post
hospitalization. In Star Ashar
and Care Supreme also, you will get claim for 60 days pre
hospitalization and 180 days post
hospitalization. But there will be no
capping of the amount in the Six Out of Six plans.
Talking about day care treatment,
all the day care treatments are covered in the Six Out of Six health insurance plans. There is
no list of any kind
nor any capping has been imposed.
If I talk about modern treatment, then it is IIC Lombard
's Elevate plan, HDFC Sir Go's
Optima Secure, Aditya Birla's  There is no capping on modern treatments in the Active
One plans, Star Assure, and Care Supreme.
All robotic surgeries are covered,
but Niva Bappa has
imposed a cap of ₹1 lakh on robotic surgeries in its Rish and plans.
E-Consultation: ICICI
Lombard's Elevate plan offers e-
Consultation, which offers unlimited teleconsultations
for any specialty.
If you avail this facility,
you can save up to ₹8,000 annually on
your outpatient department expenses.
Very few people pay attention to this feature, and
very few people are aware of it. It is a
very good feature. SDFC R&D
only offers teleconsultation for critical illnesses.
Aditya Billa does
not have this facility in Active One. Niva Bappa
Rish 2.0 will have unlimited teleconsultations.
Star Assure also does not cover this.
However,
you can avail the benefit of unlimited teleconsultation for general physicians under Care Supreme.  Now let's talk about the
revolution in health insurance. This
revolution started in 2012 with Polo
Muni bringing
restoration. Restoration will be unlimited for the
same person and same illness in ICICI Lombard Elevate plan.
Restoration will be unlimited for the same person and same
illness in HDFC Ergo. But here you will have to
take a premium of % with add-on.
In Aditya Birla Niva Bupa Star Health Care Health Insurance,
restoration is going to be unlimited for the same person and same illness
but in Niva Bupa,
once triggered, unlimited restoration will remain
triggered for life time.
Talking about ambulance,
especially road ambulance, there will be no
capping of any kind in ICICI Lombard Elevate plan. Similarly, there is no capping of any kind on road ambulance
in HDFC Ergo, Aditya
Birla Active One plan, Niva Bupa Rish 2
Plan and Star Health's Star Asher
plan. There is no capping of any kind on road ambulance in
Care Supreme
plan.  There will be a capping of ₹100,000 if
your time shot is less than ₹15,000 to ₹1 lakh. There will be
no capping for air ambulance.
ICICI Lombard has covered this as an add-on.
ICICI Lombard says that
air ambulance is used in rare cases and
not everyone needs it,
so why should every customer be penalized for it?
They have kept it as an add-on.
If you feel you need an air ambulance,
you
can avail its benefit by purchasing it as an add-on. However, in ADF Sir Go
Optima Secure, you will get an
air ambulance claim for up to 5 lakh hospitalizations in-
built. In Aditya Build, you will get
this benefit in VIP and Plus.
This variant will be available in Niva Bappa.
Star Health's
Assure plan also offers an air ambulance claim of ₹10 per of the basic sum and
you can also get it as an add-on under Care Supreme. If you
need it, then take it, otherwise there is no need.
No Claim Bonus ICICI
Lombard Elevate plan has an inbuilt No
Claim Bonus of 20% yearly and will
go up to a maximum of 100%. It will not be reduced in case of a claim.
This is a customer friendly and unique
feature. ADFC Optimum Secure has a
Secure Benefit of 50% every year.
Here your time limit will
increase by 100% every year.
Aditya Birla has a 100% time limit increase of 100%. The
inbuilt feature is
Niva B Rio 2.0. There will be a booster of
3x, 5x and 10x variants. Your
booster will be increased every year along with your basic time
limit. In Star Plan, your No Claim Bonus will
increase by 25% every year and will go up to a maximum of 100%. It will
also be reduced in case of a claim. Care
Supreme has an inbuilt No Claim
Bonus of 50% which will go up to a maximum of 100%. With add-on covers,
you get super cumulative benefits.  Bonus
can be availed in this. Talking about the next feature, the
next feature is Annual Health
Checkup. Annual Health Checkup is available here
in the IICE Labad Elevate plan with an add-on cover. If
you wish, there will be a slight premium increase,
otherwise you cannot opt ​​for it.
In ADAC Rugo, the in-built cover will be
₹5000000
and its maximum limit will be ₹1. It will be
on reimbursement basis only. Aditya Billa
Active Plan will have cashless facility
and in-built you will be given cover for annual health checkup.
In this plan also, it will be in-
built ₹5000000 and the maximum limit
will be ₹1000000 but only on cashless basis.
You will have to book your annual health checkup by going to the app.
In Star Health, you can avail in-
built annual checkup ranging from ₹00 to ₹1
but only on cashless
basis. In Care Health's Care Supreme,
you will have to take this with add-on cover.
Alternative  Treatment, which we
also call IUD treatment,
all the
treatments like Ayurvedic, Unani, Siddha, Homeopathic are covered up to six times in all the six policies
without any sub-limit.
Maternity cover is such a cover which is needed by
every person at some point in life.
You can take it in Elevate plan of ICCI Labad along with cancer cover.
This cover will be available after 2 years
at 10% off the basic sum assured and maximum limit will be
₹1 lakh. You can reduce its waiting period to
1 year also. There
is an in-build feature in hdfc0000021 off the basic sum assured. You can avail it after 2 years.
Consumer bill cover is available in ICCI Labad's
A  In the Elevate plan, you will
get ADFC R as an add-on. It will be inbuilt in Optima Secure.
Aditya Billa Active One
plan also has an inbuilt plan. In Niva Bap Rio 2
plan, you can
cover the entire list of consumables by adding Safeguard and Safeguard Plus. It will be
inbuilt in Star Assure and in Care Supreme, you can
take it as a bonus and cover a list of 68 consumable items.
Wellness
program is now being implemented in all health insurance
policies. If you take some steps per
day, keep yourself healthy and get your
tests done,
you will get a discount of up to 30% in the Elevate plan.
This facility is not available in ADFC Argo Optima Secure.
This is the USP of Aditya Billa. In Active One plan,
if you take some steps per day,
keep yourself healthy and active, then
you can get a discount of up to 100% in premium.
In Bapsh 2.0, this discount will be
30%. In Star Assure, you will get 20%
but in Care Supreme also  Here
you can avail this facility with add-ons. Now let
us talk about deductible. Deductible
is such a component in which you
can reduce your premium by bearing some part of the claim yourself.
This facility is
not available in the Elevate plan. Here there will be co-payment options but
not deductible options. There is a
difference between deductible and co-payment.
Whatever is deducted in the aggregated deductible,
you have to
bear it once a year. After that, the
insurance company pays all the claims but
you have to pay co-payment on every claim. So,
in Optima Secure, the deductible
options will be ₹25,000, ₹5,000 and ₹1 lakh. Whereas
in the Active One plan, the
premium can be reduced by taking a deductible of ₹15,000 and ₹25,000.
In Rish 2.0,
deductible options of ₹20,000, ₹50,000 and ₹1 lakh are available.
Star Assure has deductibles of ₹50,000 and ₹1 lakh,
but
deductible options will not be available in Care Supreme.
Talking about the fundamentals of the insurance company, the second part which holds the most importance is the
premium because it is the
premium that will decide whether this
health insurance plan is within your budget
or not, whether it suits your pocket
or not. So, I will talk about the premium of all these six
health insurance plans.
I have taken two options here, a
time limit of ₹1 lakh and a time limit of ₹50 lakh.
In ICICI Lombard,
I have taken the Elevate plan with unlimited time limit.
First of all, I will
talk about ICICI Lombard's Elevate plan. The
age will remain the same, 40 years for both adults and children. The
address will be in Delhi NCR. There is a
time limit of ₹10 lakh, in which I have
added a booster with an add-on, that is,
unlimited time limit will be available in it. The
premium will be only ₹
2491. Most economical here.  In the same age
group, for Delhi NCR, if you
opt for unlimited term plan,
your premium will be ₹
61,000.
Talking about Optima Secure,
ADAC Argo's premium for ₹1 lakh plan will be
₹
69,900. A little bit higher compared to
III Lord, and for ₹50 lakh plan, you will have to pay ₹
5227 for Optima Secure. Aditya Billa Active One plan will cost
you ₹7,319 for a term plan of ₹50 lakh, and if you
want to buy one for ₹8,155, you will have to pay ₹
8155. If I talk about Niva Bap Rish 2.0,
you will have to
pay ₹1 lakh plan for a term plan of ₹1 lakh, and for ₹50 lakh plan,
you will have to pay ₹993. Talking about Star Health's
Star Assur plan, it will cost ₹
32,000 for a term plan of ₹10 lakh.  It will
come for Rs 32765 and for a sum assured of Rs 50 lakh,
you will have to pay Rs 8083. Care Supreme Rs 1
lakh sum assured costs Rs 26000, Rs 498 and for a sum assured of Rs 50 lakh, Rs
8575. So Fox, this was a comparison of six health insurance
plans and in this, two health
insurance plans claim themselves to be a revolution.
Now you
decide for yourself which plan suits you,
suits your pocket.
Do check the fundamentals of the insurance company
and
also consider the fundamentals of the insurance company. So
Fox, how did you like this plan comparison?
Do give me your suggestions and your comments.
So, I will meet you in my next
video. Till then, Jai Hind, Jai Bharat.